I'm going to begin with a scary question:
[AI] 我将从一个可怕的问题开始：
Are we headed toward a future without jobs?
[AI] 我们正在走向一个没有工作的未来吗？
The remarkable progress that we're seeing
[AI] 我们看到的显著进步
in technologies like self-driving cars
[AI] 在自动驾驶汽车等技术领域
has led to an explosion of interest in this question.
[AI] 引起了人们对这个问题的极大兴趣。
but because it's something that's been asked
[AI] 但因为这是一个被问到的问题
so many times in the past.
[AI] 过去这么多次。
maybe what we should really be asking
[AI] 也许我们真正应该问的是
is whether this time is really different.
[AI] 这一次是否真的不同。
The fear that automation might displace workers
[AI] 对自动化可能取代工人的担忧
and potentially lead to lots of unemployment
[AI] 并可能导致大量失业
goes back at a minimum 200 years to the Luddite revolts in England.
[AI] 至少可以追溯到200年前英国的路德派起义。
And since then. this concern has come up again and again.
[AI] 从那时起。这种担忧一再出现。
I'm going to guess
[AI] 我猜
that most of you have probably never heard of the Triple Revolution report.
[AI] 你们大多数人可能从来没有听说过三次革命报告。
but this was a very prominent report.
[AI] 但这是一份非常突出的报告。
It was put together by a brilliant group of people --
[AI] 它是由一群才华横溢的人组成的--
it actually included two Nobel laureates --
[AI] 它实际上包括两位诺贝尔奖获得者--
and this report was presented to the President of the United States.
[AI] 这份报告被提交给了美国总统。
and it argued that the US was on the brink of economic and social upheaval
[AI] 它认为美国正处于经济和社会动荡的边缘
because industrial automation was going to put millions of people
[AI] 因为工业自动化将使数百万人
out of work.
[AI] 失业的
Now. that report was delivered to President Lyndon Johnson
[AI] 现在该报告已提交给林登·约翰逊总统
in March of 1964.
[AI] 1964年3月。
So that's now over 50 years.
[AI] 现在已经超过50年了。
and. of course. that hasn't really happened.
[AI] 和当然这并没有真正发生。
And that's been the story again and again.
[AI] 这是一个又一个故事。
This alarm has been raised repeatedly.
[AI] 此警报已多次发出。
but it's always been a false alarm.
[AI] 但这总是一个错误的警报。
And because it's been a false alarm.
[AI] 因为这是一个错误的警报。
it's led to a very conventional way of thinking about this.
[AI] 这导致了一种非常传统的思考方式。
And that says essentially that yes.
[AI] 从本质上说是的。
technology may devastate entire industries.
[AI] 技术可能会摧毁整个行业。
It may wipe out whole occupations and types of work.
[AI] 它可能会消灭所有职业和工种。
But at the same time. of course.
[AI] 但与此同时。当然
progress is going to lead to entirely new things.
[AI] 进步将带来全新的事物。
So there will be new industries that will arise in the future.
[AI] 因此，未来将出现新的行业。
and those industries. of course. will have to hire people.
[AI] 还有那些行业。当然我们必须雇人。
There'll be new kinds of work that will appear.
[AI] 将会有新的工作出现。
and those might be things that today we can't really even imagine.
[AI] 这些可能是我们今天甚至无法想象的事情。
And that has been the story so far.
[AI] 到目前为止，情况就是这样。
and it's been a positive story.
[AI] 这是一个积极的故事。
It turns out that the new jobs that have been created
[AI] 事实证明，已经创造的新工作岗位
have generally been a lot better than the old ones.
[AI] 总的来说比以前的好很多。
They have. for example. been more engaging.
[AI] 他们有。例如更吸引人。
They've been in safer. more comfortable work environments.
[AI] 他们在更安全的地方。更舒适的工作环境。
and. of course. they've paid more.
[AI] 和当然他们付出了更多。
So it has been a positive story.
[AI] 因此，这是一个积极的故事。
That's the way things have played out so far.
[AI] 到目前为止，事情就是这样发展的。
But there is one particular class of worker
[AI] 但是有一个特殊的工人阶层
for whom the story has been quite different.
[AI] 对他们来说，情况完全不同。
For these workers.
[AI] 对这些工人来说。
technology has completely decimated their work.
[AI] 技术彻底摧毁了他们的工作。
and it really hasn't created any new opportunities at all.
[AI] 而且它真的没有创造任何新的机会。
And these workers. of course.
[AI] 还有这些工人。当然
are horses.
[AI] 它们是马。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
So I can ask a very provocative question:
[AI] 所以我可以问一个非常具有挑衅性的问题：
Is it possible that at some point in the future.
[AI] 有没有可能在将来的某个时候。
a significant fraction of the human workforce is going to be made redundant
[AI] 相当一部分劳动力将被裁员
in the way that horses were?
[AI] 像马那样？
Now. you might have a very visceral. reflexive reaction to that.
[AI] 现在你可能有一个非常发自内心的想法。对此的反射反应。
You might say. "That's absurd.
[AI] 你可能会说。“那太荒谬了。
How can you possibly compare human beings to horses?"
[AI] 你怎么能把人比作马呢？"
Horses. of course. are very limited.
[AI] 马。当然它们非常有限。
and when cars and trucks and tractors came along.
[AI] 当汽车、卡车和拖拉机出现时。
horses really had nowhere else to turn.
[AI] 马真的无处可转。
People. on the other hand. are intelligent;
[AI] 人另一方面他们很聪明；
we can learn. we can adapt.
[AI] 我们可以学习。我们可以适应。
And in theory.
[AI] 从理论上讲。
that ought to mean that we can always find something new to do.
[AI] 这应该意味着我们总能找到新的事情做。
and that we can always remain relevant to the future economy.
[AI] 我们可以始终与未来经济保持关联。
But here's the really critical thing to understand.
[AI] 但这里有一件非常关键的事情需要理解。
The machines that will threaten workers in the future
[AI] 未来将威胁工人的机器
are really nothing like those cars and trucks and tractors
[AI] 真的一点也不像那些小汽车、卡车和拖拉机
that displaced horses.
[AI] 这使马流离失所。
The future is going to be full of thinking. learning. adapting machines.
[AI] 未来将充满思考。学习适应机器。
And what that really means
[AI] 这到底意味着什么
is that technology is finally beginning to encroach
[AI] 技术终于开始入侵了
on that fundamental human capability --
[AI] 关于人类的基本能力--
the thing that makes us so different from horses.
[AI] 使我们与马如此不同的东西。
and the very thing that. so far.
[AI] 正是这件事。目前为止
has allowed us to stay ahead of the march of progress
[AI] 使我们能够在前进的道路上保持领先
and remain relevant.
[AI] 并保持相关性。
and. in fact. indispensable to the economy.
[AI] 和事实上经济不可或缺。
So what is it that is really so different
[AI] 那么，到底是什么真正如此不同呢
about today's information technology
[AI] 关于今天的信息技术
relative to what we've seen in the past?
[AI] 相对于我们过去所看到的？
I would point to three fundamental things.
[AI] 我想指出三件基本的事情。
The first thing is that we have seen this ongoing process
[AI] 首先，我们看到了这一正在进行的进程
of exponential acceleration.
[AI] 指数加速。
I know you all know about Moore's law.
[AI] 我知道你们都知道摩尔定律。
but in fact. it's more broad-based than that;
[AI] 但事实上。它的基础更广泛；
it extends in many cases. for example. to software.
[AI] 它在许多情况下都会扩展。例如到软件。
it extends to communications. bandwidth and so forth.
[AI] 它延伸到通信领域。带宽等等。
But the really key thing to understand
[AI] 但真正需要理解的关键是
is that this acceleration has now been going on for a really long time.
[AI] 这种加速已经持续了很长时间。
In fact. it's been going on for decades.
[AI] 事实上这已经持续了几十年了。
If you measure from the late 1950s.
[AI] 如果你从20世纪50年代末开始测量。
when the first integrated circuits were fabricated.
[AI] 当第一批集成电路制造出来时。
we've seen something on the order of 30 doublings in computational power
[AI] 我们已经看到计算能力大约是30倍
since then. That's just an extraordinary number of times to double any quantity.
[AI] 从那时起这是任何数量翻倍的惊人次数。
and what it really means
[AI] 它的真正含义是什么
is that we're now at a point where we're going to see
[AI] 我们现在正处在一个我们将要看到的时刻
just an extraordinary amount of absolute progress.
[AI] 这绝对是一个巨大的进步。
and. of course. things are going to continue to also accelerate
[AI] 和当然事情也将继续加速发展
from this point.
[AI] 从这一点来说。
So as we look forward to the coming years and decades.
[AI] 因此，当我们展望未来几年和几十年时。
I think that means that we're going to see things that we're really not prepared for.
[AI] 我认为这意味着我们将看到我们真正没有准备好的事情。
We're going to see things that astonish us.
[AI] 我们将看到令我们惊讶的事情。
The second key thing
[AI] 第二个关键问题
is that the machines are. in a limited sense. beginning to think.
[AI] 这是机器的问题。在有限的意义上。开始思考。
And by this. I don't mean human-level AI.
[AI] 通过这个。我不是说人类水平的人工智能。
or science fiction artificial intelligence;
[AI] 或者科幻小说中的人工智能；
I simply mean that machines and algorithms are making decisions.
[AI] 我只是说机器和算法在做决定。
They're solving problems. and most importantly. they're learning.
[AI] 他们在解决问题。最重要的是。他们在学习。
In fact. if there's one technology that is truly central to this
[AI] 事实上如果有一种技术是真正的核心
and has really become the driving force behind this.
[AI] 并真正成为这背后的驱动力。
it's machine learning.
[AI] 这是机器学习。
which is just becoming this incredibly powerful.
[AI] 它正变得如此强大。
disruptive. scalable technology.
[AI] 引起混乱的可扩展技术。
One of the best examples I've seen of that recently
[AI] 这是我最近看到的最好的例子之一
was what Google's DeepMind division was able to do
[AI] 这就是谷歌的DeepMind部门能够做到的
with its AlphaGo system.
[AI] 它的AlphaGo系统。
Now. this is the system that was able to beat the best player in the world
[AI] 现在这是一个能够击败世界上最好的球员的系统
at the ancient game of Go.
[AI] 在古老的围棋比赛中。
Now. at least to me.
[AI] 现在至少对我来说是这样。
there are two things that really stand out about the game of Go.
[AI] 围棋有两件事非常突出。
One is that as you're playing the game.
[AI] 一个是当你玩游戏的时候。
the number of configurations that the board can be in
[AI] 电路板可以使用的配置数
is essentially infinite.
[AI] 本质上是无限的。
There are actually more possibilities than there are atoms in the universe.
[AI] 实际上，宇宙中存在的可能性比原子还多。
So what that means is.
[AI] 这意味着什么。
you're never going to be able to build a computer to win at the game of Go
[AI] 你永远也无法建造一台电脑来赢得围棋比赛
the way chess was approached. for example.
[AI] 下棋的方法。例如
which is basically to throw brute-force computational power at it.
[AI] 基本上就是用蛮力来计算。
So clearly. a much more sophisticated. thinking-like approach is needed.
[AI] 很清楚。一个更加复杂的系统。需要像思维一样的方法。
The second thing that really stands out is that.
[AI] 第二件真正突出的事情是。
if you talk to one of the championship Go players.
[AI] 如果你和其中一个冠军球员交谈，那就去吧。
this person cannot necessarily even really articulate what exactly it is
[AI] 这个人甚至不可能真正清楚地说出它到底是什么
they're thinking about as they play the game.
[AI] 他们一边玩游戏一边思考。
It's often something that's very intuitive.
[AI] 这通常是非常直观的。
it's almost just like a feeling about which move they should make.
[AI] 这几乎就像是一种他们应该采取什么行动的感觉。
So given those two qualities.
[AI] 考虑到这两个特点。
I would say that playing Go at a world champion level
[AI] 我想说的是，在世界冠军级别上打围棋
really ought to be something that's safe from automation.
[AI] 真的应该是不受自动化影响的东西。
and the fact that it isn't should really raise a cautionary flag for us.
[AI] 事实并非如此，这应该给我们敲响警钟。
And the reason is that we tend to draw a very distinct line.
[AI] 原因是我们倾向于画一条非常清晰的线。
and on one side of that line are all the jobs and tasks
[AI] 在这条线的一边是所有的工作和任务
that we perceive as being on some level fundamentally routine and repetitive
[AI] 我们认为在某种程度上基本上是例行的和重复的
and predictable.
[AI] 而且可以预测。
And we know that these jobs might be in different industries.
[AI] 我们知道这些工作可能在不同的行业。
they might be in different occupations and at different skill levels.
[AI] 他们可能从事不同的职业，具有不同的技能水平。
but because they are innately predictable.
[AI] 但因为它们是天生可预测的。
we know they're probably at some point going to be susceptible
[AI] 我们知道他们可能会在某个时候变得敏感
to machine learning.
[AI] 机器学习。
and therefore. to automation.
[AI] 因此。到自动化。
And make no mistake -- that's a lot of jobs.
[AI] 别搞错了，这是很多工作。
That's probably something on the order of roughly half
[AI] 这大概是一半左右
the jobs in the economy.
[AI] 经济中的就业机会。
But then on the other side of that line.
[AI] 但在那条线的另一边。
we have all the jobs that require some capability
[AI] 我们有所有需要一些能力的工作
that we perceive as being uniquely human.
[AI] 我们认为是独一无二的人类。
and these are the jobs that we think are safe.
[AI] 我们认为这些工作是安全的。
Now. based on what I know about the game of Go.
[AI] 现在根据我对围棋的了解。
I would've guessed that it really ought to be on the safe side of that line.
[AI] 我猜它真的应该在那条线的安全一边。
But the fact that it isn't. and that Google solved this problem.
[AI] 但事实并非如此，谷歌解决了这个问题。
suggests that that line is going to be very dynamic.
[AI] 这表明这条线将是非常动态的。
It's going to shift.
[AI] 它会改变的。
and it's going to shift in a way that consumes more and more jobs and tasks
[AI] 它将以一种消耗越来越多工作和任务的方式转变
that we currently perceive as being safe from automation.
[AI] 我们目前认为自动化是安全的。
The other key thing to understand
[AI] 另一个需要理解的关键问题
is that this is by no means just about low-wage jobs or blue-collar jobs.
[AI] 这绝不仅仅是低薪工作或蓝领工作。
or jobs and tasks done by people
[AI] 或者人们做的工作和任务
that have relatively low levels of education.
[AI] 教育水平相对较低的。
There's lots of evidence to show
[AI] 有很多证据可以证明
that these technologies are rapidly climbing the skills ladder.
[AI] 这些技术正在迅速提升技能。
So we already see an impact on professional jobs --
[AI] 因此，我们已经看到了对专业工作的影响--
tasks done by people like accountants.
[AI] 由像会计师这样的人完成的任务。
financial analysts.
[AI] 金融分析师。
journalists.
[AI] 记者。
lawyers. radiologists and so forth.
[AI] 律师。放射科医生等等。
So a lot of the assumptions that we make
[AI] 所以我们做了很多假设
about the kind of occupations and tasks and jobs
[AI] 关于职业、任务和工作的类型
that are going to be threatened by automation in the future
[AI] 未来将受到自动化的威胁
are very likely to be challenged going forward.
[AI] 很可能在未来受到挑战。
So as we put these trends together.
[AI] 所以我们把这些趋势放在一起。
I think what it shows is that we could very well end up in a future
[AI] 我认为这表明我们很可能在未来结束
with significant unemployment.
[AI] 失业率高企。
Or at a minimum.
[AI] 或者至少。
we could face lots of underemployment or stagnant wages.
[AI] 我们可能面临大量的就业不足或工资停滞。
maybe even declining wages.
[AI] 甚至可能是工资下降。
And. of course. soaring levels of inequality.
[AI] 和当然不平等程度不断加剧。
All of that. of course. is going to put a terrific amount of stress
[AI] 所有这些。当然会给你带来巨大的压力
on the fabric of society.
[AI] 在社会结构上。
But beyond that. there's also a fundamental economic problem.
[AI] 但除此之外。还有一个根本的经济问题。
and that arises because jobs are currently the primary mechanism
[AI] 这是因为工作是目前的主要机制
that distributes income. and therefore purchasing power.
[AI] 分配收入。因此，购买力。
to all the consumers that buy the products and services we're producing.
[AI] 所有购买我们生产的产品和服务的消费者。
In order to have a vibrant market economy.
[AI] 为了有一个充满活力的市场经济。
you've got to have lots and lots of consumers
[AI] 你必须有很多很多的消费者
that are really capable of buying the products and services that are being produced.
[AI] 他们确实有能力购买正在生产的产品和服务。
If you don't have that. then you run the risk
[AI] 如果你没有。那你就去冒险
of economic stagnation.
[AI] 经济停滞。
or maybe even a declining economic spiral.
[AI] 甚至可能是经济螺旋式下降。
as there simply aren't enough customers out there to buy the products and services being produced.
[AI] 因为根本没有足够的客户来购买正在生产的产品和服务。
It's really important to realize
[AI] 认识到这一点非常重要
that all of us as individuals rely on access to that market economy
[AI] 我们每个人都依赖于进入市场经济
in order to be successful.
[AI] 为了成功。
You can visualize that by thinking in terms of one really exceptional person.
[AI] 你可以用一个真正与众不同的人来想象这一点。
Imagine for a moment you take. say. Steve Jobs.
[AI] 想象一下你所做的一切。说史蒂夫·乔布斯。
and you drop him on an island all by himself.
[AI] 你把他一个人扔到岛上。
On that island. he's going to be running around.
[AI] 在那个岛上。他会到处乱跑。
gathering coconuts just like anyone else.
[AI] 像其他人一样采集椰子。
He's really not going to be anything special.
[AI] 他真的不会有什么特别的。
and the reason. of course. is that there is no market
[AI] 以及原因。当然就是没有市场
for him to scale his incredible talents across.
[AI] 让他展示自己不可思议的才能。
So access to this market is really critical to us as individuals.
[AI] 因此，进入这个市场对我们个人来说是非常关键的。
and also to the entire system in terms of it being sustainable.
[AI] 以及整个系统的可持续性。
So the question then becomes: What exactly could we do about this?
[AI] 所以问题就变成了：我们到底能做些什么？
And I think you can view this through a very utopian framework.
[AI] 我认为你可以通过一个非常乌托邦的框架来看待这一点。
You can imagine a future where we all have to work less.
[AI] 你可以想象一个我们都必须少工作的未来。
we have more time for leisure. more time to spend with our families.
[AI] 我们有更多的时间休闲。有更多的时间和家人在一起。
more time to do things that we find genuinely rewarding and so forth.
[AI] 更多的时间去做我们认为真正值得做的事情等等。
And I think that's a terrific vision.
[AI] 我认为这是一个很棒的愿景。
That's something that we should absolutely strive to move toward.
[AI] 这是我们绝对应该努力实现的目标。
But at the same time. I think we have to be realistic.
[AI] 但与此同时。我认为我们必须实事求是。
and we have to realize
[AI] 我们必须意识到
that we're very likely to face a significant income distribution problem.
[AI] 我们很可能面临一个重大的收入分配问题。
A lot of people are likely to be left behind.
[AI] 很多人可能会被甩在后面。
And I think that in order to solve that problem.
[AI] 我认为为了解决这个问题。
we're ultimately going to have to find a way
[AI] 我们最终必须找到一条路
to decouple incomes from traditional work.
[AI] 使收入与传统工作脱钩。
And the best. more straightforward way I know to do that
[AI] 而且是最好的。我知道的更直接的方法是这样做
is some kind of a guaranteed income or universal basic income.
[AI] 是某种有保障的收入或普遍的基本收入。
Now. basic income is becoming a very important idea.
[AI] 现在基本收入正在成为一个非常重要的概念。
It's getting a lot of traction and attention.
[AI] 它得到了很大的吸引力和关注。
there are a lot of important pilot projects
[AI] 有许多重要的试点项目
and experiments going on throughout the world.
[AI] 以及世界各地正在进行的实验。
My own view is that a basic income is not a panacea;
[AI] 我个人的观点是，基本收入不是万能药；
it's not necessarily a plug-and-play solution.
[AI] 它不一定是即插即用的解决方案。
but rather. it's a place to start.
[AI] 而是。这是一个开始。
It's an idea that we can build on and refine.
[AI] 这是一个我们可以建立和完善的想法。
For example. one thing that I have written quite a lot about
[AI] 例如有一件事我写了很多
is the possibility of incorporating explicit incentives into a basic income.
[AI] 是将明确的激励措施纳入基本收入的可能性。
To illustrate that.
[AI] 为了说明这一点。
imagine that you are a struggling high school student.
[AI] 想象一下，你是一个挣扎的高中生。
Imagine that you are at risk of dropping out of school.
[AI] 想象一下你有辍学的危险。
And yet. suppose you know that at some point in the future.
[AI] 然而。假设你在将来的某个时候知道这一点。
no matter what.
[AI] 不管怎样。
you're going to get the same basic income as everyone else.
[AI] 你将获得和其他人一样的基本收入。
Now. to my mind. that creates a very perverse incentive
[AI] 现在在我看来。这就产生了一种非常反常的激励
for you to simply give up and drop out of school.
[AI] 让你放弃学业，辍学。
So I would say. let's not structure things that way.
[AI] 我可以这么说。让我们不要那样安排事情。
Instead. let's pay people who graduate from high school somewhat more
[AI] 相反让我们给高中毕业的人多付点钱
than those who simply drop out.
[AI] 而不是那些直接辍学的人。
And we can take that idea of building incentives into a basic income.
[AI] 我们可以将激励措施纳入基本收入。
and maybe extend it to other areas.
[AI] 也许可以扩展到其他领域。
For example. we might create an incentive to work in the community
[AI] 例如我们可以创造一种在社区工作的激励
to help others.
[AI] 帮助别人。
or perhaps to do positive things for the environment. and so forth.
[AI] 或者也许是为了对环境做一些积极的事情。等等
So by incorporating incentives into a basic income.
[AI] 因此，通过将激励措施纳入基本收入。
we might actually improve it.
[AI] 我们可能会改进它。
and also. perhaps. take at least a couple of steps
[AI] 还有。可能至少采取两个步骤
towards solving another problem
[AI] 解决另一个问题
that I think we're quite possibly going to face in the future.
[AI] 我认为我们很可能会在未来面对。
and that is. how do we all find meaning and fulfillment.
[AI] 就是这样。我们如何找到意义和实现。
and how do we occupy our time
[AI] 我们如何打发时间
in a world where perhaps there's less demand for traditional work?
[AI] 在一个对传统工作需求较少的世界里？
So by extending and refining a basic income.
[AI] 因此，通过扩大和完善基本收入。
I think we can make it look better.
[AI] 我想我们可以让它看起来更好。
and we can also. perhaps. make it more politically and socially acceptable
[AI] 我们也可以。可能让它在政治上和社会上更容易被接受
and feasible --
[AI] 切实可行--
and. of course. by doing that.
[AI] 和当然通过这样做。
we increase the odds that it will actually come to be.
[AI] 我们增加了它真正实现的可能性。
I think one of the most fundamental.
[AI] 我认为这是最基本的问题之一。
almost instinctive objections
[AI] 几乎是本能的反对
that many of us have to the idea of a basic income.
[AI] 我们中的许多人不得不接受基本收入的概念。
or really to any significant expansion of the safety net.
[AI] 或者说是对安全网的任何重大扩张。
is this fear that we're going to end up with too many people
[AI] 是不是担心我们会有太多的人
riding in the economic cart.
[AI] 坐在经济车上。
and not enough people pulling that cart.
[AI] 而且拉车的人还不够多。
And yet. really. the whole point I'm making here. of course.
[AI] 然而。真正地我在这里说的全部要点。当然
is that in the future.
[AI] 这是将来的事。
machines are increasingly going to be capable of pulling that cart for us.
[AI] 机器越来越有能力为我们拉车。
That should give us more options
[AI] 这应该给我们更多的选择
for the way we structure our society and our economy.
[AI] 我们构建社会和经济的方式。
And I think eventually. it's going to go beyond simply being an option.
[AI] 我想最终。这将不仅仅是一种选择。
and it's going to become an imperative.
[AI] 这将成为当务之急。
The reason. of course. is that all of this is going to put
[AI] 原因。当然这一切都会使
such a degree of stress on our society.
[AI] 我们的社会承受着如此程度的压力。
and also because jobs are that mechanism
[AI] 也因为工作是一种机制
that gets purchasing power to consumers
[AI] 这让消费者获得了购买力
so they can then drive the economy.
[AI] 这样他们就能推动经济。
If. in fact. that mechanism begins to erode in the future.
[AI] 如果事实上这一机制在未来开始削弱。
then we're going to need to replace it with something else
[AI] 然后我们需要用别的东西来代替它
or we're going to face the risk
[AI] 否则我们将面临风险
that our whole system simply may not be sustainable.
[AI] 我们的整个系统可能根本不可持续。
But the bottom line here is that I really think
[AI] 但这里的底线是我真的认为
that solving these problems.
[AI] 解决这些问题。
and especially finding a way to build a future economy
[AI] 特别是找到一条建设未来经济的道路
that works for everyone.
[AI] 这对每个人都适用。
at every level of our society.
[AI] 在我们社会的各个层面。
is going to be one of the most important challenges that we all face
[AI] 这将是我们所有人都面临的最重要的挑战之一
in the coming years and decades.
[AI] 在未来的几年和几十年里。
Thank you very much.
[AI] 非常感谢你。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）